[
  {
    "question": "Spell the following words: a) Eisteddfod  b) Drunkenness.",
    "answer": "Eisteddfod and Drunkenness"
  },
  {
    "question": "What figure of speech is the phrase “Autumn arrived in his coat of orange, red and gold?”",
    "answer": "Personification"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the author of the book “To Kill A Mockingbird,” who died on February 19th 2016?",
    "answer": "Harper Lee"
  },
  {
    "question": "What term is given to a figure of speech in which two successive words seemingly contradict one another as in “wise fool”?",
    "answer": "Oxymoron"
  },
  {
    "question": "What word in English is the only word that ends in the letters 'mt'.",
    "answer": "Dreamt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What sentence in English uses all the letters of the English alphabet?",
    "answer": "The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city or country would you find The Spanish Steps?",
    "answer": "Rome and Italy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Turkey’s highest mountain?",
    "answer": "Mount Ararat"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which war did Florence Nightingale nurse help the injured?",
    "answer": "Crimean War"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the capital cities of the following countries: a.) Qatar – Doha  b.) Indonesia – Jakarta.",
    "answer": "Doha and Jakarta"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tourist attraction in Zimbabwe is a result of chemical weathering?",
    "answer": "Chinhoyi Caves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tanzania is a portmanteau name (two-word combination) from which two states which united in 1964?",
    "answer": "Tanganyika and Zanzibar"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Multinational Joint Task Force is a combined army aimed at destroying Boko Haram in Nigeria. Besides Nigeria, name the other countries involved?",
    "answer": "Chad, Niger, Benin, and Cameroon"
  },
  {
    "question": "List Zimbabwe’s two natural sites listed on World Heritage list?",
    "answer": "Victoria Falls and Mana Pools"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country is the Skeleton Coast National Park found?",
    "answer": "Namibia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the two languages commonly spoken in Africa which are not of European origin?",
    "answer": "Arabic and Swahili"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the African city named after a US President, and what was his full name?",
    "answer": "Monrovia and James Monroe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Liberated American slaves formed their own country in Africa. Name this country?",
    "answer": "Liberia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are numbers 6, 28, and 496 examples of?",
    "answer": "Perfect Numbers (they are equal to sum of all their factors)"
  },
  {
    "question": "If, during a mathematical conversion, you multiplied by 5 and divided by 8, what would you be converting?",
    "answer": "Miles to kilometres"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the letters LASER stand for?",
    "answer": "Light Amplification by the Stimulated Emission of Radiation"
  },
  {
    "question": "If it takes 5 men to dig 5 holes in 5 hours, how many men does it take to dig 100 holes in 100 hours?",
    "answer": "20 men - each man digs 1 hole in 5 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "What virtual digital currency, divided into 100 million units called satoshis, was created by developer Satoshi Nakamoto in 2008?",
    "answer": "Bitcoin"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, ADSL stands for what?",
    "answer": "Asymmetric Digital Subscriber Line"
  },
  {
    "question": "What date has been set for the 2023 Zimbabwe elections?",
    "answer": "Wednesday 23 August 2023"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which member of the K-Pop band ASTRO died on 19 April 2023? How old was he?",
    "answer": "Moon Bin and 25"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the finalists of the Champions League 2023?",
    "answer": "Manchester City and Inter Milan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is the International symbol for happiness?",
    "answer": "Bluebird"
  },
  {
    "question": "What color is the blood of an octopus?",
    "answer": "blue"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the new Nigerian President?",
    "answer": "Bola Ahmed Tinubu"
  }
]